Everyone is
using
anti-gravity
wrong.
They open it
up, ask random
questions, copy
paste whatever
it gives and
then wonder why
your code
is a mess.
I did this
through four
weeks and was
really
frustrating.
But after
building 10
plus projects
using
anti-gravity,
not demos, I
figured out a
workflow that
actually works.
A system and
today I'm going
to show you
exactly
how to do it.
By the end of
this video you
have the exact
system I use
and to prove it
works we're
going to
build this.
A markdown to
slide your
converter from
scratch.
Let's go.
Before we build
you need to
understand why
most people
fail with
anti-gravity.
Most people
just chat, ask
questions, get
code, paste it,
ask another
question, get
more code, then
repeat.
The problem?
No structure,
no plan.
You end up with
Frankenstein
code that
nobody can
maintain
including you.
And the worst
part is
anti-gravity is
insanely
powerful.
That's why I
developed the
Vibe code
protocol.
A structured
way to work
with the AI.
Three phrases,
Genesis
design build.
But first let
me show you how
to set it up.
Step one, open
anti-gravity.
Press Ctrl L to
open the agents
panel if it's
not
already open.
Click on these
three
dots here.
Click on
customizations,
workflows, then
create a new
one on that
global.
Type anything
you want.
Right
click on that.
Click on show
file location.
Delete that
random file.
Drop in the
workflow files.
I'll link these
below the like
button
completely
free.
Now when I type
forward slash
and chart I see
all my
workflows.
That's
the setup.
Let's use it.
The single
biggest
mistake,
writing code
before you have
a plan.
I'm going to
build the
markdown to
slide your
converter.
But I'm not
going to ask
for code yet.
I'm going to
run Genesis.
tell it build
an app where it
picks the
markdown and it
turns into a
swipable
slide deck.
Watch what
happens.
Now we're going
to set it up
for five mostly
because I find
that it's very
very good at
planning.
And all this is
available for
you for free in
anti-gravity
depending on
what plan
you're on.
So you
get to go.
So you can see
it's asking us
some questions.
This is mostly
because we
haven't given
it a lot of
information.
Pro tip here
for example if
I'm going to
pull up like a
professional
projector I've
worked on in
the past.
I usually spend
a lot of time
feeding in a
lot of
information.
For example
inside the idea
I dump this.
You see this
this is a full
voiceover
transcribe of
what my plan is
for this
project.
So by the time
I'm coming back
into
anti-gravity I
don't really
need to spend
that much time
explaining
all this.
So now I've
answered every
single question
that I asked me
and I just
hit enter.
So I'm just
going to
accept this.
Now let me show
you a cool
feature that
anti-gravity
actually has.
If you open the
agents manager
here at the top
and you select
the project
you're
presently on.
For example
this I've
launched a
project.
This is one.
I can see the
charts we are
having in the
editor but it's
here now.
And then here I
can pull up
this side panel
here and this
is where
anti-gravity is
going to drop
what we call
artifacts.
Basically any
file that
anti-gravity
edits will show
up here.
Boom as you can
see it just
updated this
file just now.
It generates a
full project
requirement
document.
Every feature
every user
story coding
guidelines
specific to
this project.
It generates
prompts that
act as the AI's
instruction
manual.
And then we can
just look at the
implementation
plan it has.
So it tells us
that okay this
is the plan
this is the
goal this is
this and you
can review
all this.
If you don't
like anything
it has said
here you can
basically see
how I
highlighted
this and I can
just comment
and be like oh
tweak this
tweak that add
a comment it
shows here you
submit the end.
It just
basically works
like Google
Docs at
this point.
This is
in code.
This is the
blueprint.
Now when I ask
for code later
it knows the
context.
It knows
the rules.
No more
explaining
myself
over and over.
That's the
first phase.
Genesis measure
twice cut once.
But most people
would jump
straight into
code now.
That's
completely
wrong.
There's one
more step.
What if I told
you
anti-gravity
could design
your whole UI
without writing
any code.
Phase two is
design.
Running it now.
And switch back
to Gemini
3 Pro now.
Wow.
So it has
brought me a
brief for me to
review.
It asks what
the vibe is.
I might go for
minimal clean
maybe
dark mode.
I tell you what
I want and it
generates a
custom design
system with the
colors I choose
or if I don't
have any it
chooses colors
for me.
Fonts spacing
HTML mockups
for the editor
and slide
preview.
Look at this.
I haven't
written a
single line of
code but I can
already see the
app and the
builder
followed this
exactly.
I didn't want
to put this out
here that from
experience I
figured out
that this is
way better than
asking the AI
to generate an
image of what a
mockup could be
because
sometimes it
just ends up
coughing out
things that are
literally so
hard to
build on UI.
So telling it
to write this
HTML code kind
of grounds it
in what is
possible.
Phase three.
Now we code.
So in a new
chart just to
make sure that
the AI is fresh
choose whatever
model you want.
You can use
Opos45 Gemini 3
whichever one
you want at
this
point is fine.
It's fair
because you
just
scaffold in.
So we're going
to write
five code.
The difference
between this
two actually
boils down to
two things.
In here we use
PNPM which is a
package manager
and here
we use MPM.
Recently I
started using
PNPM so I just
made sure that
we use it.
So that's what
we're going to
use for
this demo.
Enter.
You could open
the terminal
that
Antigravity is
running here.
You could open
it here to look
at it and see
all things that
are happening
and that we hit
accept.
Hitting accept
every time can
be very
annoying
for you.
If you come to
the Antigravity
settings here
you come to
advanced
settings you'll
be able to turn
on like review
policy, make it
that it always
proceeds.
For this I'll
just keep it to
review request
review.
Therefore
terminal
commands are
always proceed.
However just
some things
that are added
to the
permission
allow list and
also
denial list.
This is your
choice.
Also be very
careful with
how you do
things here.
You understand
that kind
of thing.
Auto open
edited files.
I turned this
one off but
basically what
it does is as
the file is
tripping it
opens them up
automatically.
It's your
choice
honestly.
Auto fix links
is a very good
addition
to add.
Auto continue
is a good
addition to
these two are
good additions.
Under the
browser section
honestly as you
go ideally
request review
is good.
If you want to
be like me you
can just accept
oh that's fine
I guess.
So just play
around with the
settings and
figure out what
you
really like.
Do well to
provide
feedback.
That's a very
good habit too.
The builder
reads the PR
reads the
mock-ups and
scaffolds the
entire project.
It's creating
the structure
implementing
the features
from the PRD
matching the
design.
So now
it's done.
I'll just have
to approve this
so that it
checks for
errors.
It's going to
do its own
self-check to
see if there
are any errors.
We close it all
off with a full
breakdown from
the AI telling
us exactly what
it did and how
we can run this
project.
So you
see done.
Now I can come
here and
basically just
write PMPM Dev.
Beautiful
actually.
Beautiful actually.
Beautiful
beautiful
beautiful.
Mastering the
prompts.
Okay and there
it is running a
markdown to
slide through
converter.
Typing some
markdown.
Hit preview
slides.
Three phases.
Genesys
design build.
That's the
entire
workflow.
Kinda.
But what if I
want to add
something.
That's where
the daily loops
kicking.
Let's add
keyboard
navigation
using arrow
keys to flip
the slides.
I don't just
say add a
keyboard nav.
That's
terrible.
I use the daily
workflow.
Step one.
Declare what
I'm doing.
It keeps the AI
focused.
Step two.
Make the
changes.
AI as a pair
programmer.
Step three.
Close it out.
Document what
it's done.
Now just an
extra bonus to
help you out.
If you notice
it created a
GitHub issues
folder.
Now this file
what you can
simply do is to
just basically
select an issue
like this and
you could click
on this and be
like implement.
I just hit
enter and then
he just goes
implement that
once it's done
and you like
what it did you
click on the
next and say
implement.
Enter.
That way you
make sure that
you're only
feeding the
agent what it
needs to
implement at a
particular
time.
And if you
check your
project
requirement
document here.
Let me actually
preview this
for you
properly.
This is what
the document
properly
looks like.
I see a table a
raised form of
your
description
user story
expected
behavior and
outcome.
Breaking down
exactly what
the application
should do to
the AI so that
it doesn't miss
any
single thing.
And then once
you're done
with the MOS
and you confirm
that the
minimum usable
state is done
then you can
migrate to
attending to
future
requirements.
These are the
much more
advanced things
that will take
your
application
from just a
demo project to
something
that's actually
outstanding.
So let's
test it.
The arrow works
the feature
added and
it's clean.
That's how you
iterate.
The system
keeps you on
track even
after the
initial build.
Three phases.
Genesis design build.
Then you use
the daily loop
to keep
iterating.
All the work
full files are
shown are
linked below
the like
button.
Three.
Grab them.
If this helped
subscribe.
I've got more
advanced
tutorials
coming up like
running
multiple agents
simultaneously
on the same
code base.
Drop in
comments what
you will be
using the
system and I'll
see you in the
next one.
Code with
the vibe.
the flow.